Hamilton, ON, Canada nicholas.dahl@mohawkcollege.ca

Nick Dahl

linkedin.com/in/nick-dahl github.com/nckdhl nckdhl.com

I am a motivated software developer and student at Mohawk College, changing careers after spending several years in the farming and construction equipment industries. In 2020, I gathered valuable software industry experience during two co-op work terms. Now I'm seeking an internship/co-op for summer 2021 at a company where I can make an impact and learn.

Technologies and Languages

Languages and frameworks: Javascript (Node.js/Express, Mocha, React), Java, C#, PHP, Python, SQL
 Technologies and tools: Firebase, ELK Stack, relational databases, Linux, Ansible, Git, Tomcat, Ant

Other: Data structures and algorithms, Object-oriented design

Relevant Work Experience

eHealth Software Developer (co-op)

Ideaworks MEDIC
Hamilton, Ontario

May 2020 – Dec 2020

- Built and shipped REST API for search feature using Java EE that integrated into legacy health record app.
- Leveraged Webpack and vanilla Javascript to update important billing UI without overhead of frontend framework.
- Collaborated on key feature that converted user assets (.docx, .tiff, .txt, etc.) to PDF using open-source Java libraries.
- Independently researched, built and documented POC Elastic Stack (ELK) installation to solve distributed logging problem for a client with complex Node.js microservices architecture.
- Leveraged Ansible to automate the configuration of ELK and microservices in AWS and on-prem KVM environment.

QA Developer (contractor)

Solo Digitalis

March 2020 - May 2020

- Hamilton, Ontario
- Researched and designed test plan for Node.js REST API running on Firebase Cloud Functions.
- Made a key technical decision to use Mocha to automate testing of dozens of endpoints resulting in 100% coverage.
- Came up with an innovative method for seeding Firestore database with mock users and data for integration tests.
- Leveraged Selenium web driver to automate E2E testing of React.js app.

Online Store Manager

Peter & Pat Seifenblasen

Jan 2015 - Jan 2020

Berlin, Germany / Remote

- Co-managed a successful online store with thousands of customers from across Europe each year.
- Developed excellent ability to rapidly troubleshoot by resolving bugs in production website.
- Redesigned Wordpress/Woocommerce site to achieve improved order conversion rate.

Education

• **Software Development** - 3.5 year Advanced Diploma, Mohawk College (*in progress*)

Sept 2018 - Dec 2021

Projects

- VOIP In-browser client | github.com/nckdhl/vanilla-client-node
 - Successfully built and deployed a full-stack web app that uses Twilio's Voice API to make and receive calls.
- Portfolio Website | nckdhl.com
 - o Built and deployed to Netlify, a SPA using React.js

Other Work Experience

Field Service Technician Bartell Global 2016 – 2018

Mississauga, Ontario

- Completed critical on-site repairs of industrial surface preparation equipment.
- Used technical knowledge to diagnose and fix electrical problems with industrial drives.
- Maintained a strong working relationship with key accounts, ensuring they received exceptional service.
- Collaborated with international engineering and sales teams to identify technical issues, drive new equipment sales and provide after-sales support.

Farmer

Stolze Kuh Ecological Farm

2015 - 2016

Stolzenhagen, Germany

- Strengthened a small team of founders who started a first-of-its-kind organic dairy farm in eastern Germany, by contributing my agricultural skills and holistic management experience.
- Showcased my ability to perform under pressure, work well in a team and prioritize tasks.

Livestock Operations Manager

Whole Circle Farm

2013 - 2014

Acton, Ontario

- Responsible for the management of all livestock production at Whole Circle organic farm.
- Led the modernization of dairy infrastructure and practices, leading to improved animal health and production.
- Gained skills in onboarding and training by overseeing apprentices and mentoring my successor.

Accomplishments

- Achieved working fluency in the German language in under one year after moving to Berlin (2010)
- Co-founded and organized a community garden for a halfway house at the Berlin City Mission (2012)
- Dedicated volunteer at large homeless shelter and other social projects at Berlin City Mission (2010 2011, 2015)

Interests

- I am passionate about organic farming. In my spare time, I enjoy exploring the intersection of IoT and agriculture.
- I am an avid carpenter. I have completed major and minor renovations around my house with fantastic results.
- I love languages. I am currently teaching myself Polish to converse with my in-laws overseas.